<article>
  <preamble>kesslerMETICS-ICDIM2019.pdf</preamble>
  <titre>A word embedding approach to explore a collection of discussions of people in psychological distress Universite Bretagne Sud </titre>
  <auteurs>
    <auteur>Remy Kessler </auteur>
    <affiliation>Universite Bretagne SudCNRS 6074A56017 Vannes,Franceremy.kessler@univ-ubs.fr</affiliation>
    <auteur>Nicolas Bechet</auteur>
    <affiliation>2nd Nicolas BechetUniversite Bretagne SudCNRS 6074A56017 Vannes,Francenicolas.bechet@irisa.fr</affiliation>
  </auteurs>
  <abstract>Abstract&#8212;In order to better adapt to society, an associationhas developed a web chat application that allows anyone toexpress and share their concerns and anguishes. Several thousandanonymous conversations have been gathered and form a newcorpus of stories about human distress and social violence. Wepresent a method of corpus analysis combining unsupervisedlearning and word embedding in order to bring out the themesof this particular collection. We compare this approach with astandard algorithm of the literature on a labeled corpus andobtain very good results. An interpretation of the obtainedclusters collection confirms the interest of the method.Keywords&#8212;word2vec, unsupervised learning, word embedding.</abstract>
  <biblio>No references was found</biblio>
  <conclusion>VI. CONCLUSION AND FUTURE WORKIn this article, we presented an unsupervised approach toexploring a collection of stories about human distress. Thisapproach uses a word embedding model to build vectorscontaining only vocabulary from the linguistic context of themodel. We evaluated the quality of the approach on a col-lection labeled with classical measures. The detailed analysisshowed very good results (average Fscore of 0.54) comparedto the other systems tested. This method of analysis has alsomade it possible to highlight semantic universes and thematicgroupings. We first intend to study in more detail the influenceof each of the parameters on the results obtained. We are alsoplanning to be able to assign several tags to each discussion,which would allow thematic overlaps to be taken into account.The analysis reinforces the cluster approach to highlight thedefining features of this type of speech production and toreveal its inner workings. This entry by the discursive routinesis only one example which will then make it possible toapproach other explorations with a particular focus on theargumentative forms and on the forms of intensity.REFERENCES[1] D. Fassin, &#8220;Et la souffrance devint sociale,&#8221; in Critique.680(1), 2004,pp. 16&#8211;29.[2] &#8212;&#8212;, &#8220;Souffrir par le social, gouverner par l&#8217;ecoute,&#8221; in Politix.73(1),2006, pp. 137&#8211;157.[3] MacQueen, J., &#8220;Some methods for classification and analysis of multi-variate observations,&#8221; in Proceedings of the Fifth Berkeley Symposiumon Mathematical Statistics and Probability, Vol. 1: Statistics.USA:University of California Press, 1967, pp. 281&#8211;297.[4] D. Arthur and S. Vassilvitskii, &#8220;K-means++: The advantages of carefulseeding,&#8221; Proceedings of the Eighteenth Annual ACM-SIAM Symposiumon Discrete Algorithms, pp. 1027&#8211;1035, 2007.[5] L. Kaufman and P. Rousseeuw, Clustering by Means of Medoids.DelftUniversityofTechnology:reportsoftheFacultyofTechnical Mathematics and Informatics, 1987. [Online]. Available:https://books.google.fr/books?id=HK-4GwAACAAJ[6] G. N. Lance and W. T. Williams, &#8220;A general theory of classificatorysorting strategies1. hierarchical systems,&#8221; The Computer Journal 4, pp.373&#8211;380, 1967.[7] A. P. Dempster, N. M. Laird, and D. B. Rubin, &#8220;Maximum likelihoodfrom incomplete data via the em algorithm,&#8221; in Journal of the royalsociety, series B, 1977, pp. 1&#8211;38.[8] J. D. Banfield and A. E. Raftery, &#8220;Model-based gaussian and non-gaussian clustering,&#8221; in Biometrics, vol. 49, 1993, pp. 803&#8211;821.[9] T. Kohonen, &#8220;Self-organized formation of topologically correct featuremaps,&#8221; Biological Cybernetics, pp. 59&#8211;69, Jan 1982.[10] U. N. Raghavan, R. Albert, and S. Kumara, &#8220;Near linear time algorithmto detect community structures in large-scale networks.&#8221; Physical review.E, Statistical, nonlinear, and soft matter physics, p. 036106, 2007.[11] J. P. Pestian, P. Matykiewicz, M. Linn-Gust, B. South, O. Uzuner,J. Wiebe, K. B. Cohen, J. Hurdle, and C. Brew, &#8220;Sentiment analysisof suicide notes: A shared task,&#8221; Biomedical Informatics Insights, pp.3&#8211;16, 2012.[12] A. Abboute, Y. Boudjeriou, G. Entringer, J. Aze, S. Bringay, andP. Poncelet, &#8220;Mining twitter for suicide prevention,&#8221; in Natural LanguageProcessing and Information Systems: 19th International Conference onApplications of Natural Language to Information Systems, NLDB 2014,Montpellier, France, June 18-20, 2014. Proceedings.Springer, 2014,pp. 250&#8211;253.[13] R. Kessler, J.-M. Torres, and M. El-Beze, &#8220;Classification thematique decourriel par des methodes hybrides,&#8221; Journee ATALA sur les nouvellesformes de communication ecrite, 2004.[14] T. Mikolov, I. Sutskever, K. Chen, G. Corrado, and J. Dean, &#8220;Distributedrepresentations of words and phrases and their compositionality,&#8221; inProceedingsofNIPS&#8217;13.USA:CurranAssociatesInc.,2013,pp. 3111&#8211;3119. [Online]. Available: http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2999792.2999959[15] C. D. Manning and H. Sch&#168;utze, Foundations of Statistical NaturalLanguage Processing.Cambridge, MA, USA: MIT Press, 1999.[16] C. Goutte and E. Gaussier, &#8220; A Probabilistic Interpretation of Precision,Recall and F-Score, with Implication for Evaluation,&#8221; ECIR 2005, pp.345&#8211;359, 2005.[17] M. Hoffman, F. R. Bach, and D. M. Blei, &#8220;Online learning for latentdirichlet allocation,&#8221; in Advances in Neural Information ProcessingSystems, J. D. Lafferty, C. K. I. Williams, J. Shawe-Taylor, R. S. Zemel,and A. Culotta, Eds.23, 2010, pp. 856&#8211;864.</conclusion>
</article>
