<article>
  <preamble>kessler94715.pdf</preamble>
  <titre>Extraction of terminology in the field of construction Universite Bretagne Sud </titre>
  <auteurs>
    <auteur>Remy Kessler </auteur>
    <affiliation>Universite Bretagne SudCNRS 6074A56017 Vannes,Franceremy.kessler@univ-ubs.fr</affiliation>
    <auteur>Nicolas Bechet</auteur>
    <affiliation>3rd Giuseppe BerioUniversite Bretagne SudCNRS 6074A56017 Vannes,Francegiuseppe.berio@univ-ubs.fr</affiliation>
  </auteurs>
  <abstract>Abstract&#8212;We describe a corpus analysis method to extractterminology from a collection of technical specifications in thefield of construction. Using statistics and word n-grams analysis,we extract the terminology of the domain and then performpruning steps with linguistic patterns and internet queries toimprove the quality of the final terminology. Results are evaluatedby using a manual evaluation carried out by 6 experts in the field.Index Terms&#8212;terminology extraction, Internet queries, linguis-tic patterns.</abstract>
  <biblio>No references was found</biblio>
  <conclusion>VII. CONCLUSION AND PERSPECTIVESThe paper reports our experiments and results for buildinga precise and large terminology for the construction domain.Collecting terminology is indeed the first step towards acomplete knowledge model containing both concepts andrelationships. During our work we were faced to severalproblems: finding resources and selecting them for buildingan appropriate corpus, thinking and developing pre-processingfor cleaning those resources, experimenting distinct measuresfor n-grams and selecting the most appropriate, improvingresults by adding linguistic patterns and Internet queries. Thecurrent results are quite promising according to the evaluationof the extracted terminology carried out by 6 experts in thefield. As a perspective, we will develop generic modules andguidelines for adapting these pre-processing modules to otherlanguages. Most importantly, the results of our work are usefulfor extracting taxonomical and non-taxonomical relationships.For the both purposes, we are currently working on SemEvalcollection [26]. Applying our method to other domain corporaand datasets is another future direction for this research.REFERENCES[1] S. Meignier and T. Merlin, &#8220;Lium spkdiarization: an open source toolkitfor diarization,&#8221; in in CMU SPUD Workshop, 2010.[2] P. Pauwels and W. Terkaj, &#8220;Express to owl for construction industry:Towards a recommendable and usable ifcowl ontology,&#8221; Automation inConstruction, vol. 63, pp. 100&#8211;133, 03 2016.[3] H. Cunningham, &#8220;Gate, a general architecture for text engineering,&#8221; inComputers and the Humanities, vol. 36, 2002, pp. 223&#8211;254.[4] P. Cimiano and J. V&#168;olker, &#8220;text2onto,&#8221; in International conference onapplication of natural language to information systems. Springer, 2005,pp. 227&#8211;238.[5] P. Kluegl, M. Toepfer, P.-D. Beck, G. Fette, and F. Puppe, &#8220;Uima ruta:Rapid development of rule-based information extraction applications,&#8221;Natural Language Engineering, vol. 22, no. 1, p. 1&#8211;40, 2016.[6] M. Roche and Y. Kodratoff, &#8220;Exit: Un systeme iteratif pour l&#8217;extractionde la terminologie du domaine `a partir de corpus specialises,&#8221; inProceedings of JADT 4, 2004, pp. 946&#8211;956.[7] B. Biebow, S. Szulman, and A. J. B. Clement, &#8220;Terminae: A linguistics-based tool for the building of a domain ontology,&#8221; in KnowledgeAcquisition, Modeling and Management, D. Fensel and R. Studer, Eds.,1999, pp. 49&#8211;66.[8] P. Drouin, &#8220;Term extraction using non technical corpora as point of lever-age,&#8221; in John Benjamins Publishing Company: Amsterdam/Philadelphia,n. Terminology, vol. 9, Ed., 2003, pp. 99&#8211;115.[9] M. F. M. Chowdhury, A. M. Gliozzo, and S. M. Trewin, &#8220;Domain-specific terminology extraction by boosting frequency metrics,&#8221; Sep. 272018, uS Patent App. 15/469,766.[10] G. Bouma, &#8220;Normalized (pointwise) mutual information in collocationextraction,&#8221; Proceedings of GSCL, 2009.[11] Y. Bestgen, &#8220;Evaluation de mesures d&#8217;association pour les bigrammes etles trigrammes au moyen du test exact de fisher,&#8221; Proceedings of TALN2017, pp. 10&#8211;19, 2017.[12] A. L. Meyers, Y. He, Z. Glass, J. Ortega, S. Liao, A. Grieve-Smith,R. Grishman, and O. Babko-Malaya, &#8220;The termolator: Terminologyrecognition based on chunking, statistical and search-based scores,&#8221;Frontiers in Research Metrics and Analytics, vol. 3, p. 19, 2018.[13] L. Gillam, M. Tariq, and K. Ahmad, &#8220;Terminology and the constructionof ontology,&#8221; TERMINOLOGY, vol. 11, pp. 55&#8211;81, 2005.[14] A. Panchenko, S. Faralli, E. Ruppert, S. Remus, H. Naets, C. Fairon, S. P.Ponzetto, and C. Biemann, &#8220;TAXI at semeval-2016 task 13: a taxonomyinduction method based on lexico-syntactic patterns, substrings andfocused crawling,&#8221; in Proceedings of the 10th International Workshopon Semantic Evaluation, SemEval@NAACL-HLT 2016, San Diego, CA,USA, June 16-17, 2016, 2016, pp. 1320&#8211;1327.[15] E.Lefever,L.Macken,andV.Hoste,&#8220;Language-independentbilingual terminology extraction from a multilingual parallel corpus,&#8221;in Proceedings of the 12th Conference of the European Chapterof the Association for Computational Linguistics, ser. EACL &#8217;09.Stroudsburg, PA, USA: Association for Computational Linguistics,2009, pp. 496&#8211;504. [Online]. Available: http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1609067.1609122[16] L. Macken, E. Lefever, and V. Hoste, &#8220;Texsis: bilingual terminologyextractionfromparallelcorporausingchunk-basedalignment,&#8221;Terminology, vol. 19, no. 1, pp. 1&#8211;30, 2013. [Online]. Available:http://dx.doi.org/10.1075/term.19.1.01mac[17] G. Dias and H.-J. Kaalep, &#8220;Automatic extraction of multiword unitsfor estonian : Phrasal verbs,&#8221; in Languages in Development, 2003, p.41:81&#8211;91.[18] B. Daille, &#8220;Study and implementation of combined techniques forautomatic extraction of terminology,&#8221; The Balancing Act: CombiningSymbolic and Statistical Approaches to Language, 12 2002.[19] C. Lang, R. Schneider, and K. Suchowolec, &#8220;Extracting specializedterminology from linguistic corpora,&#8221; GRAMMAR AND CORPORA, p.425, 2018.[20] E. Amjadian, D. Inkpen, T. S. Paribakht, and F. Faez, &#8220;Local-globalvectors to improve unigram terminology extraction,&#8221; in Proceedings ofthe 5th International Workshop on Computational Terminology, 2016.[21] G. Wohlgenannt and F. Minic, &#8220;Using word2vec to build a simpleontology learning system.&#8221; in International Semantic Web Conference(Posters &amp; Demos), 2016.[22] H. Schmid, &#8220;Probabilistic part-of-speech tagging using decision trees,&#8221;1994.[23] E. Altman, &#8220;Financial ratios, discriminant analysis and the predic-tion of corporate bankruptcy.&#8221; in The Journal of Finance, 23(4).doi:10.2307/2978933, 1968, pp. 589&#8211;609.[24] J. Cohen, &#8220;A Coefficient of Agreement for Nominal Scales,&#8221; Educationaland Psychological Measurement, vol. 20, no. 1, p. 37, 1960.[25] M. L. McHugh, &#8220;Interrater reliability: the kappa statistic,&#8221; in Biochemiamedica, 2012.[26] M. Apidianaki, S. M. Mohammad, J. May, E. Shutova, S. Bethard,and M. Carpuat, &#8220;Proceedings of the 12th international workshop onsemantic evaluation,&#8221; in Proceedings of The 12th International Workshopon Semantic Evaluation.Association for Computational Linguistics,2018. [Online]. Available: http://aclweb.org/anthology/S18-1000</conclusion>
</article>
