<article><preamble>Nasr.pdf</preamble><titre /><auteur>MACAON &amp; Alexis Nasr &amp; Fr&#233;d&#233;ric B&#233;chet &amp; Jean-Franc&#184;ois Rey &amp; Beno&#710;&#305;t Favre &amp; Joseph Le Roux&#8727;</auteur><abstract>AbstractMACAON is a tool suite for standard NLP tasksdeveloped for French. MACAON has been de-signed to process both human-produced textand highly ambiguous word-lattices producedby NLP tools. MACAON is made of several na-tive modules for common tasks such as a tok-enization, a part-of-speech tagging or syntac-tic parsing, all communicating with each otherthrough XML files . In addition, exchange pro-tocols with external tools are easily definable.MACAON is a fast, modular and open tool, dis-tributed under GNU Public License.1</abstract><biblio>ReferencesAnne Abeill&#233;, Lionel Cl&#233;ment, and Franc&#184;ois Toussenel.2003.Building a treebank for french.In AnneAbeill&#233;, editor, Treebanks. Kluwer, Dordrecht.Steven Abney. 1996. Partial parsing via finite-state cas-cades. In Workshop on Robust Parsing, 8th EuropeanSummer School in Logic, Language and Information,Prague, Czech Republic, pages 8&#8211;15.M. Attia, J. Foster, D. Hogan, J. Le Roux, L. Tounsi, andJ. van Genabith. 2010. Handling Unknown Words inStatistical Latent-Variable Parsing Models for Arabic,English and French. In Proceedings of SPMRL.Lucie Barque, Alexis Nasr, and Alain Polgu&#232;re. 2010.From the definitions of the tr&#233;sor de la langue franc&#184;aiseto a semantic database of the french language. In EU-RALEX 2010, Leeuwarden, Pays Bas.Fr&#233;d&#233;ric B&#233;chet and Alexis Nasr. 2009. Robust depen-dency parsing for spoken language understanding ofspontaneous speech. In Interspeech, Brighton, UnitedKingdom.Olivier Blanc, Matthieu Constant, and Eric Laporte.2006. Outilex, plate-forme logicielle de traitement detextes &#233;crits. In TALN 2006, Leuven.Nancy Ide and Laurent Romary.2004.Internationalstandard for a linguistic annotation framework. Nat-ural language engineering, 10(3-4):211&#8211;225.M. Mohri, F. Pereira, and M. Riley. 2000. The designprinciples of a weighted finite-state transducer library.Theoretical Computer Science, 231(1):17&#8211;32.P. Nocera, G. Linares, D. Massoni&#233;, and L. Lefort. 2006.Phoneme lattice based A* search algorithm for speechrecognition. In Text, Speech and Dialogue, pages 83&#8211;111. Springer.Slav Petrov, Leon Barrett, Romain Thibaux, and DanKlein. 2006. Learning Accurate, Compact, and In-terpretable Tree Annotation. In ACL.Beno&#710;&#305;t Sagot and Pierre Boullier.2008.Sxpipe 2:architecture pour le traitement pr&#233;syntaxique de cor-pus bruts.Traitement Automatique des Langues,49(2):155&#8211;188.Beno&#710;&#305;t Sagot, Lionel Cl&#233;ment, Eric Villemonte de laClergerie, and Pierre Boullier. 2006. The lefff 2 Syn-tactic Lexicon for French: Architecture, Acquisition,Use.In International Conference on Language Re-sources and Evaluation, Genoa.Andreas Stolcke. 2002. Srilm - an extensible languagemodeling toolkit. In International Conference on Spo-ken Language Processing, Denver, Colorado.S.J. Young.1994.The HTK Hidden Markov ModelToolkit: Design and Philosophy. Entropic CambridgeResearch Laboratory, Ltd, 2:2&#8211;44.91</biblio></article>